A Guide to the Virginia Governor George F. Allen Policy Office Records, 1993-1998
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Governor George F. Allen Policy Office Records, 1993-1998
The Library of Virginia
35860 and 35864
3.525 cu. ft (5 boxes)
Virginia. Governor (1994-1998: Allen)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred by Georgia Root, Assistant Secretary of the Commonwealth, Richmond, Virginia, 19 June 1998.
Biographical Information
George Felix Allen was born March 8, 1952 in Whittier, California to famed NFL football coach George H. Allen and his wife Henrietta (Lumbroso) Allen. He graduated from the University of Virginia in 1971 and the University of Virginia School of Law in 1977. Allen served in the Virginia House of Delegates from 1982-1991 and served a short term in the U.S. House of Delegates in the early 1990s. In November 1993, Allen beat Attorney General Mary Sue Terry to become Governor. Governor Allen served until January 1998 and was suceeded by Governor James S. Gilmore. Governor Allen has been married to Susan (Brown) Allen since 1986 and they have three children, Forrest, Tyler, and Brooke. The family resides in Mount Vernon, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Contains correspondence, reports, speeches, minutes, and clippings related to various policies with which the Allen administration was concerned. The topics covered include federalism, federal government interference in Virginia affairs, education policies, the use of inmate labor, the proposed Walt Disney theme park in Prince William County, Virginia, and the Virginia-Israel Partnership. Also included are a variety of uncategorized files related to transportation issues, community development, environmental policy, the budget, and taxation.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Federalism Files
Series II. Education Files
Series III. Inmate Labor Files
Series IV. Federal Interference Files
Series V. Miscellaneous Files
Series VI. Disney's America Files
Series VII. Virginia-Israel Partnership Files
Contents List
- Series I. Federalism Files, 1994-1997., Extent: .5 cu. ft. (Box 1)
  Contains records documenting the Allen administration's efforts to reduce federal government influence on Virginia state government. The material documents administration efforts to address the perceived inbalance in power between the state and federal government. The records also include several files related to the activities of the Advisory Council on Self-Determination and Federalism. Additional records related to federal government interference can be found in Series IV. Federal Interference Files.
  Arranged according to subject.
  - Federalism: Governor's Working Papers, 1995 April-1996 March. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - New Veto Provision of Constitution (Parental Rights Amendment), 1995 February-March. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Federalism Summit, 1995 October. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "The Conference of the States: An Action Plan to Restore Balance in the Federal System," by Mike Leavitt, undated. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Advisory Council on Self-Determination and Federalism (Correspondence), 1995 February-1996 April. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Federalism Correspondence, 1995 November. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Advisory Council on Self-Determination and Federalism (Addresses), 1995 August. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Research Concerning Federalist Papers, undated. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Unfunded Mandates (Report), 1995 April. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Subcommittee on Unfunded Mandates (Report), 1995 October-November. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Advisory Council on Self-Determination and Federalism (Notices), 1995 April-July. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Federalism Council, Subcommittee Number 2 (Meetings and Notes), 1995 January-July. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Federalism Council, Subcommittee Number 4 (Materials), 1995 February-August. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Federalism Council, Subcommittee Number 4 (Meetings and Notes), 1995 April-June. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Federalism Council, Subcommittee Number 5 (Meetings and Notes), 1995 February-April. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Articles for Federalism Council Meeting, 1995 May. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Federalism Summit (Talking Points), 1995 October. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - States' Initiative and States' Veto Background, 1996 June. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Federal Council, States' Veto (Report), 1995 September. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Federalism Speeches (Becky Norton Dunlop), 1996 March. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Federalism Speeches and Memos (Governor Allen), 1996 September-October. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Federalism Speeches, Southern Governors'Association/ALEC (Governor Allen), 1995 September-October. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Federal Issues (Press Releases), 1995 October-1997 May. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - States' Initiative Correspondence (Governor Allen to Tom Bliley), 1997 June. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Federalism Council, Speeches and Press Releases (Governor Allen, John Ashcroft), 1994 November-1996 July. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Williamsburg Resolve (Copy of), 1994. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "States' Veto and States' Initiative...," Subcommittee on Constiutional Amendments (Final Report), undated. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Federalism (National Governors' Association), 1995 January. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Federal Interference, Dept. of Education (Report), 1995 October. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Executive Order Number 37, 1994 November. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Federal Interference Assessment (Copy of), undated. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Arlen Specter/Goals 2000 (Correspondence), 1995 October. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - "Devolution of the Employment Security System to the States...," 1996 January. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Commonwealth of Virginia et al v. United States of America et al. (National Voter Registration Act), 1995 August. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Conference of the States (Resolution), 1995 January. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - H.R. 2270, 1995 September; 1996 April. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - States' Rights and States' Initiative Documents, 1996 March. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Article V. Proposal of the Council of State Governments to National Association for a Balanced Federal System, 1989. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - ALEC Profile of Governor Allen, 1995 May. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - "A Federalist Perspective on the Crime Problem," Panel Presentation by Governor Allen (Published in Cornell Journal of Law and Public Policy), 1995. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Conservative Political Action Committee (Speech), 1996 February. (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Federalism Summit: Restoring Balance in the Federal System, 1995 October-December. (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Federalism Summit (Governor Allen Letter to), 1995 October. (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Series II. Education Files, 1994-1998., Extent: .9 cu. ft. (Box 1-2)
  Contains records concerning Allen administration educational policies and initiatives. This material contains information on Virginia Standards of Accreditation and Goals 2000. The records include speeches, memorandums, and press releases.
  - Higher Education: 1994 Virginia Military Institute Commencement Speech, 1994 May. (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Higher Education: University of Virginia/Medical College of Virginia Hospital Privatization, 1996 January. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Higher Education: Affirmative Action and Admission Policies, 1996 January. (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Higher Education: Decentralization of Higher Education, 1997 January. (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Virginia School Boards Association: Contract on Higher Education, 1995 June-October. (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - National Governors' Association: Policies on Education, 1996 May-June. (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Free Lunch Feasibility Study, 1994 September-November. (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Virginia Commission for the Arts, Non-State Agency Funding, 1996 March-April. (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools (Final Report), 1996 January. (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Governor Allen's Contact with Former U.S. Education Secretary Bill Bennett (Memorandum), 1994 September. (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Medical College of Virginia Hospitals Authority and the Commonwealth's Risk Management Plan (Memoranda), 1997 July. (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Jamestowne Society, 1997 April. (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Student Record Confidentiality (Bills before General Assembly), 1996 January. (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Education, Legislative and Budget Announcements (Memoranda), 1996 December. (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Tuition Contracts (Memoranda), 1996 February. (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Funding School Choice (Vouchers and Tax Credits), undated. (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Charter Schools, 1997 January-February. (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Education: Governor's Working Papers, 1994-1996. (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Fairfax County Teacher's Federation (Press Release), 1997 February. (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Standards of Accreditation: Public Comments on, 1997 August. (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Standards of Accreditation: Survey, 1997 January. (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Standards of Accreditation: Endorsements, 1997 April. (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Standards of Accreditation: Customer Correspondence, 1997 May-September. (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Standards of Accreditation: Governor Allen's Letter to the President of the Virginia Board of Education, 1997 May. (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Standards of Accreditation: Memos from Diane Atkinson, 1997 May-June. (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Standards of Accreditation: Corrections to, 1997 February. (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Standards of Accreditation: Memoranda, 1997 May. (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Standards of Accreditation: Memoranda, 1997 April. (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Standards of Accreditation: Diploma Requirements and Testing Issues, 1997 February-June. (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Standards of Accreditation: Publicity Packet, 1997 August-September. (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Standards of Accreditation: Publicity Packet, 1996 December-1997 February. (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Standards of Accreditation: Final Comments by Board of Education, 1997 June. (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Standards of Accreditation: Written Comments Related to, 1997 April. (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Standards of Accreditation: Written Comments Related to, 1997 April. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Standards of Accreditation: News Clippings, 1997. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Standards of Accreditation: Proposed Amendments to, 1997 June. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Standards of Accreditation: Regulations Establishing Standards for Accrediting Public Schools in Virginia, 1997 September. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Standards of Accreditation: Regulations Establishing Standards for Accrediting Public Schools in Virginia, 1997 June. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Standards of Accreditation: Regulations Establishing Standards for Accrediting Public Schools in Virginia, 1997 March. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Standards of Accreditation: Regulations Establishing Standards for Accrediting Public Schools in Virginia, 1997 February. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Standards of Accreditation: Regulations, Summaries, Explanations and Comparisons, 1997 August-October. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Legislative Records (Miscellaneous), 1997. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - School Report Cards (Memoranda and Copies), 1998 January. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Goals 2000: Letter from Attorney General's Office, 1996 March. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Goals 2000: Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1997 June. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Goals 2000: Executive Memorandum 11-94, 1994. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Goals 2000: Announcement Concerning, 1997 January. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Goals 2000: Correspondence between Governor Allen and Senator Gregg, 1996 September. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Goals 2000: Correspondence, 1996 April-June. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Goals 2000: Application for Grant, 1995-1997. (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Series III. Inmate Labor Files, 1995-1997., Extent: .2 cu. ft. (Box 2)
  Contains reports, correspondence, news clippings, and speeches concerning the use of inmate labor under the Allen administration. The files include those related to the Community Work Project Program, the history of inmate labor in Virginia, and the establishment of Convicted Offenders Serving Virginia (CONSERV).
  - Community Work Project Program: "Ideas that Work," undated. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Community Work Project Program: Monthly Reports, 1996. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Community Work Project Program: Thank-you Letters from Localities, 1995-1996. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Inmate Labor: Press Clippings, 1995-1997. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Inmate Labor: Code of Virginia, undated. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Inmate Labor: Conservation Work Corps (Decision Memoranda), 1995 October. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Inmate Labor: Governor Allen's Speeches, 1995 October-November. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Inmate Labor: Joint Memorandum Establishing Convicted Offenders Serving Virginia (CONSERV), 1995 December. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Inmate Labor: History of Inmate Labor in Virginia, undated. (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Series IV. Federal Interference Files, 1994-1996., Extent: .4 cu. ft. (Box 2)
  Contains records documenting perceived interference by the federal government in Commonwealth of Virginia affairs. Included are Federal Interference Assessments completed by secretariats and various departments. The assessments include information regarding the impact of state and federal mandates on local government, as well as analysis and recommendations put forth by the individual Cabinet Secretaries. Additional records related to federalism and states' rights can be found in Series I. Federalism Files.
  - Federal Interference Assessments: Secretariat of Health and Human Resources, 1995 December. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Federal Interference Assessments: Secretariat of Natural Resources, 1995 March. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Federal Interference Assessments: Secretariat of Public Safety, 1995 April. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Federal Interference Assessments: Secretariat of Transportation, 1995 May. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Assessment of Local Mandates: Dept. of Aviation, 1995 October. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Dept. of Planning and Budget's Response to Federal Interference Assessment from Virginia Military Institute, 1996 August. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Completed Assessments of Local Mandates (Memoranda), 1995 May-1996 June. (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Federal Interference Assessments: Secretariat of Commerce and Trade, 1995 November. (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Federal Interference Assessments: Secretariat of Finance, 1994 August. (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Federal Interference Assessments: Secretariat of Education, 1995 August. (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Federal Interference Assessments: Secretariat of Education, 1996 June. (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Federal Interference Assessments: Secretariat of Education, 1995 August. (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Series V. Miscellaneous Files, 1993-1997., Extent: .6 cu. ft. (Box 3)
  Contains a variety of records including reports, correspondence, and memoranda. Included are documents concerning budget issues, transportation issues, crime, the environment, and tax policy. Records regarding the Secretariats of Commerce and Trade and Health and Human Resources are available, as are folders devoted to the Governor's Commission on Competitive and Equitable Tax Policy.
  - The State of the Commonwealth's Debt: Secretary of Finance Report to Governor Allen, 1997 November. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Debt Capacity Advisory Committee Report to the Governor and General Assembly, 1997 December. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Transportation (Correspondence), 1995 July-1996 December. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Commerce and Trade (Memoranda), 1995 June-1997 June. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Natural Resources, 1995 June-1997 October. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Health and Human Resources, 1995 June-1997 April. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Health and Human Resources, 1994 June-1997 April. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Finance, 1994 May-1996 March. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Dept. of Housing and Community Development, 1994 January. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Commerce and Trade: Virginia Housing Development Authority, 1996 November. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Commerce and Trade: Virginia Employment Commission, 1994 February. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Commerce and Trade: Virginia Employment Commission (Devolution), 1995 September. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Commerce and Trade: Tourism Task Force, 1995 January. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Commerce and Trade: Urban Partnership, 1995 June-December. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Commerce and Trade: Center for Innovative Technology, 1994 December. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Commerce and Trade: Baseball Stadium Authority, 1997 January. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Commerce and Trade: Virginia Economic Development Partnership (Enterprise Zone Study), 1996 February. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Commerce and Trade: Minority Farmers, 1997 June. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Commission on Competitive and Equitable Tax Policy, 1996 September. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Commission on Competitive and Equitable Tax Policy, 1996 November. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Commission on Competitive and Equitable Tax Policy: Agenda and Presentations, 1996 July. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Commission on Competitive and Equitable Tax Policy: Appointments, 1996 May. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Commission on Competitive and Equitable Tax Policy: Individual Income Tax, 1997 September. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Commission on Competitive and Equitable Tax Policy: Tangible Personal Property Tax, 1997 October. (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Commission on Competitive and Equitable Tax Policy: BPOL Subcommittee, 1997 September. (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Commission on Competitive and Equitable Tax Policy: Sales Tax, 1997 September. (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Commission on Competitive and Equitable Tax Policy: Survey, 1997 March. (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Governor's Virginia History Initiative: Come Home to Virginia History, 1996 August-September. (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Outdoor Advertising Association of Virginia, 1995 August. (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Governor's Commission on Environmental Stewardship, 1996 June-August. (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Dept. of Environmental Quality: Ozone Transport Commission, 1994 January. (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Dept. of Conservation and Recreation: Coastal Nonpoint Pollution Control Boundary, 1994 November. (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Child Care Issues, undated. (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Poison Control Services, 1996 July-August. (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Health and Human Resources: Safe Drinking Water Announcement, 1994 May. (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Family Impact Statement, 1995 July. (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Health and Human Resources: Dentists' Licensure by Endorsement, 1994 March. (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Health and Human Resources: Diagnosis Related Grouping Projects, 1996 December. (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Earned Income Tax Credit, 1995 October. (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Health and Human Resources: Optometry Legislation, 1994 December. (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Health and Human Resources: Welfare Reform (Correspondence), 1995 February. (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Health and Human Resources: Virginia Independence Plan (Welfare Reform Initiative), 1995. (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - National Governors' Association: Welfare Reform Questionnaire, 1994 April-May. (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - R.G.A. Ballot: Welfare Reform, 1995 October. (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Health and Human Resources: Welfare Reform (Waiver Resolution), 1994 January. (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Veteran's Issues: American Legion Speech, 1993 July. (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Parental Rights Amendment, undated. (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Dept. of Transportation: VDT Strike Force Recommendations, 1995 June. (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Dept. of Transportation: V.P.A. Procurement Policies and Procedures, 1997 January. (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Salary Disparity Issue: CASK, 1994 March. (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Convicted Offenders Serving Virginia (CONSERV), 1995 December. (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Dept. of Corrections: Amendments to the Private Corrections Management Act, 1994 September. (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Second Annual Governor's Forum on Crime: Speech, 1996 October. (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Crime Bills and Crime Legislation (Press Release), 1994 March. (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - VRS to Governor's Policy Office: Senate Bill 2008 (Memorandum), 1994 July. (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Dept. of Taxation: Harper v. Virginia Refund Estimate, 1995 September. (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Tax: United States GATS Reservations, 1994 June. (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Small Employer Health Insurance Availability Model Act (Memorandum), 1995 March. (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Budget Legality Takling Points: House Bills 29 and 30, 1996. (Box 3, Folder 59)
- Series VI. Disney's America Files, 1994., Extent: .5 cu. ft. (Box 3-4)
  Contains documents related to Walt Disney's proposed Disney's America history theme park in Prince William County, Virginia. The Walt Disney company drew up plans for a history theme park in the early 1990s, but the project was eventually canceled. The project was supported by Governor Allen, but it was criticized for its proximity to Manassas National Battlefield Park, and for promoting "corporate history," a toned-down version of actual events skewed for entertainment purposes. Records include news clippings, speeches, testimony, correspondence, and press conference material.
  - Congressman Mike Andrews Resolution, 1994 June. (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Disney Hearings Briefing Memoranda, 1994 June-September. (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Briefing Book for Congressional Hearing, 1994 March-June. (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Testimony from Congressional Hearing, 1994 June. (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Testimony from Congressional Hearing, 1994 June. (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Larry King Live Transcript/Letter to Governor Allen from Senator Warner, 1994 February-September. (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Press Clippings, 1994 September-October. (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Press Clippings, 1994 January-September. (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - General Correspondence, 1994 April. (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Legislation as of 15 February 1994, 1994 February. (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Legislation after 15 February 1994, 1994 March. (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Transportation Issues, 1994 January-February. (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Press Conference, 1994 February. (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Host Committee Letters, 1994 January. (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Materials from Briefing, 1994 January. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Invitation Letters to General Assembly for Briefing, 1994 January. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Rezoning Issues and Relocation Proposal, 1994 January. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Disney FOIA Requests and Miscellaneous Issues, 1994 February. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Series VII. Virginia-Israel Partnership Files, 1994-1997., Extent: .425 cu. ft. (Box 4-5)
  Contains records related to the Virginia-Israel Partnership, which was created by Governor George Allen in 1995. This partnership was established to explore opportunities to expand economic and cultural links between the Commonwealth of Virginia and the State of Israel and to advise the Governor's Office on such matters. Records include correspondence, reports, minutes, and clippings.
  Arranged alphabetically according to subject.
  - Advisory Board Members, 1996-1997. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Annual Report, 1997. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Arts and Education Committee: Correspondence and Minutes, 1995. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Arts and Education Committee: Teacher Exchange, 1996-1997. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Arts and Education Committee: Haifa Art Exchange, 1995-1996. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Arts and Education Committee: Weizmann Institute, 1996. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Arts and Education Committee: High Schools, 1996. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Arts and Education Committee: Museums, 1995. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Arts and Education Committee: Art Exchanges, 1996. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Beit Shemesh (Mayor), 1997. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Business Seminar, 1996. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Commerce and Trade Outline, 1995. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1997. (Box 4, Folder 17)